#### Personal data

Name: **Alexander Krikun**Date of Birth: **02/16/2000**E-mail: **krikun.contact@ya.ru** 

krikun.contact@gmail.com

GitHub: github.com/krikuff

#### Tech skills

- C, C++, Rust, Bash
- Git, Make, CMake, Clang, GCC, gdb
- Linux, SQLite, Memcached
- C++ STL, Boost, OpenCV (C++)
- GitHub, GitLab, Jira, MS TFS

### Summary of qualification

I have started programming in C++ in the 2017. In 2017 – 2018 I have been writing simple control systems for Arduino-based robots. Since then I worked part-time as Linux serverside software developer for such companies as EleSy and InfoTeCS. I think of myself as **Junior+developer** or **Middle-ish developer** because I have experience with big C++ projects.

#### Education

 2018 – 2022 / Currently enrolled in the "Computer science and engineering" BS program / TUSUR (Tomsk State University of Control Systems and Radioelectronics) / Tomsk, Russian Federation

#### About me

- I had been participating in international stage of RoboCup robotics championship twice (RoboCup Asia-Pacific 2017, 2018);
- I have no pernicious habits;
- I can learn quick and ready to do it;
- My native language is Russian, also I speak English (B2).

## Experience

C/C++ Software engineer (part-time)		<u>infotecs.ru</u>	
Term	Oct 2020 – now		
Project	Quantum encryption security system – a hardware-software solution for quantum key distribution.		
Technologies	Linux, C++ STL, Boost, Bash, embedded C		
My impact	Besides participating in developing the core logic, I support the embedded software part of the project.		
C++ Software engineer (part-time)		<u>elesy.ru</u>	
Term	Mar 2020 – Oct 2020		
Project	SNMP subsystem (based on net-snmp) and security subsystem		
Technologies	Linux, C++ STL, C, net-snmp		
My impact	I learned general principles of team work. In exchange I brought the practice of compile time checks to the projects I worked with.		

## Competitive robotics

C++ Software engineer			
Project	<b>Rescue robot control system</b> for RoboCup championship, Junior Rescue Maze league		
Task	Create a robot which finds it's way in a maze according to league rules		
Term	Feb 2019 – Apr 2019		
Team	1 software engineer, 1 circtuit engineer		
Technologies	C++, Make, OpenCV, Linux, Raspberry Pi		
My impact	I developed the control system. Also I implemented the environment analysis system based on lasers. This approach let us use only one camera as sensor subsystem (instead of many sonars).		
Result	The robot was passing the maze		
Embedded C++ Software engineer			
Project	<b>Soccer robot control system</b> for RoboCup championship, Junior Soccer Open league		
Task	Create 2 wheeled robots which play soccer according to the league rules		
Term	May 2017 – Dec 2018		
Team	1 software engineer, 1 circuit engineer		
Technologies	C++, Arduino		
My impact	I developed: behavioral scenarios for robots, control system architecture, interfaces and libraries which let me quickly rewrite scenarios during competition days		
Result	The cooperation of Japanese, Iranian and our (Russian) team earned the SuperTeam Champion award in RoboCup Asia-Pacific 2017 in Thailand. Our team took 8th place in RoboCup Asia-Pacific 2018 in Iran.		

# Other projects

C Backend Developer		github.com/krikuff/fcgi-redir
Project	"FastCGI Redirector", a take-home assignment for an IT company	
Term	Aug 2019	
Task	Create a multithreaded backend application (http server), which redirects user from one URL to another. Redirection depends on the key in user's URL query. The key-URL pairs are stored in MySQL and have to be cached to Memcached. The server have to communicate with Nginx using FastCGI protocol and have to be written in C.	
Technologies	C, Make, Linux, Nginx, MySG	L, Memcached, POSIX
My impact		lication. I reduced redirection latency by using ace comparing to the usual blocking interface.
Result	Take-home assignment was accepted but I didn't land my job in the company because I couldn't fit my University schedule with full-time job.	